postnl.post 2018-06-27

# Privacy Statement | PostNL

## What is personal data?

‘Personal data’ refers to data which provides information about you or which we can somehow relate to you, such as your name and address. You might share personal information with us in the following situations:

  * You are a PostNL customer.
  * You have been in contact with us.
  * You have been using one or several of our services.

If you visit our website or use our app, you may, in some cases, share personal data with us.

## Why do we process your personal data?

We process your personal data because we seek to provide you with personalised services. We use information relating to you which we have stored for this purpose, so as to enable us to assist you as quickly and efficiently as we can if you have any questions regarding any of our services. By ‘processing’, we mean storing, analysing, altering/updating/modifying, deleting, forwarding, etc.

## How do we use your personal data?

Below you can read about the various ways in which we use your personal data.

### 1\. We do our work

### 2\. We will notify you when your parcel is on the way

### 3\. We make sure the PostNL-app works properly

### 4\. We make sure the PostNL website works properly

### 5\. Sometimes we share your data with authorities

### 6\. We improve our services

### 7\. We provide you with interesting information on our website and the PostNL-app

### 8\. We prevent fraud

### 9\. We read job applicants’ CVs

### 10\. We use our employees’ personal data

## Whom does PostNL collect personal data from?

We keep personal data from anyone who has been in contact with us either directly or indirectly. An example of indirect contact is if you order an item from an online retailer and PostNL delivers the parcel to your home. In this case, you have not shared your address with us personally, but we receive it from the retailer instead.   
We are also in possession of personal data relating to contacts, representatives and vendors with whom we maintain business relationships.

## What types of personal data do we process?

Below is a list of the categories of personal data we process:

### Mail delivery

### Parcel delivery

### Storage service

### Digital Stamps

### Forwarding Service

### Next-of-kin Service

### Online Shipping Tool

### Relocation Service

### PostNL’s website and app

### PostNL’s app

### Your feedback on PostNL and about PostNL on social media

### Your PostNL account

### Customer service

### If you are applying to PostNL

### If you are a PostNL employee

## With whom do we share this personal data?

As a rule, we do not share your data with any individuals or organisations outside PostNL, except when this is necessary to provide the service we have promised you, for example if you are using our Relocation Service. In this case, you indicate which companies should receive your address change through PostNL. In some cases, we may be required to provide personal data, for example when reporting cases of fraud. The following organisations are entitled by law to request data from us in specific cases:   

  * Law enforcement agencies
  * Judicial organisations
  * Regulators such as the Dutch Data Protection Authority (AP) and the Authority for Consumers & Markets (ACM)
  * Tax and Customs Administration (Belastingdienst)

## How long do we store your data?

We generally do not retain your data any longer than necessary. How long we keep your data depends on the following factors:   

  * For what purpose do we store your data?
  * How long are we required by law to store the data?

## How do we protect your personal data?

We seek to treat your data with the highest level of security in the following ways:   

  * We spend a significant amount of time and money on protecting our systems containing personal data. We have a specific department for this purpose: Cybersecurity.
  * If there is a problem involving our security, causing people outside PostNL to be able to view the personal data, or if there is a situation which creates a risk of the data being compromised, we make a record of this and handle the situation with care. We report these incidents to the regulator, and, if necessary, to you.
  * Only employees who require access to your data can view this data. All our employees have signed a non-disclosure agreement (NDA), which remains in force even after they have left the company.
  * Our data processing operations are supervised by two organisations and a dedicated Data Protection Officer: 
    * The Dutch Data Protection Authority (AP) monitors whether we comply with the General Data Protection Regulation.
    * The Authority for Consumers & Markets (ACM) monitors whether we deal appropriately with: 
      * Cookies
      * Direct marketing
      * The National Do Not Call Registry (bel-me-niet-register)
    * The Data Protection Officer monitors whether PostNL handles personal data appropriately, and its legal duties are provided for under the law. The Data Protection Officer reports directly to the management board. If you have any questions for the Data Protection Officer, please send an e-mail to: [fg@postnl.nl](mailto:fg@postnl.nl).

## What are your rights in relation to the personal data we store on you?

You are permitted to perform the following acts with the personal data we keep on you:

  * View/access
  * Update/correct
  * Restrict
  * Delete
  * Object to the processing of the data
  * Receive the data in a manner that enables you to easily share it with others

 **Viewing and updating your data in your PostNL account  
** You can view and update your data in the following ways:

  * If you hold a PostNL account, you will see what data we store on you. There are many details you can change on the spot.
  * Please use [this form](https://www.postnl.nl/en/privacy-statement/request-or-update-personal-data/ "Request or update your personal data") to request or update your personal data. Alternatively, you can also object to the processing of your personal data.
  * If you have no computer or do not wish to send an e-mail, please send a letter, enclosing a copy of your identity document (for example, a passport or driving licence). Please note: make sure your Citizen Service Number/Burgerservicenummer (if applicable) is invisible on the copy of your ID. We request that you also write down the date and the reason for sending us a copy. This is a way of preventing fraud. Please send your letter, along with a copy of your ID, to the following address:

PostNL   
Privacy Office   
Verzoek persoonsgegevens (Personal data request)   
Postbus 30250   
2500 GG The Hague 

You will receive a reply by mail, so as to prevent others from viewing your personal data.

## About this Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement applies to all businesses and services featuring the PostNL logo and was created on 23 May 2018. This Privacy Statement is subject to change.

## Do you have any questions about privacy?

If you have any questions after reading this Privacy Statement about how we use your personal data, please contact our Customer Service department or our Data Protection Officer: [fg@postnl.nl](mailto:fg@postnl.nl).   
Of course, we hope that we answer your privacy-related questions correctly. If you are nevertheless dissatisfied with our response, please submit a complaint to the Dutch Data Protection Authority (Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens).
